♪The stars remember♪
♪सितारे याद रखते हैं♪
♪The promise we made to each other♪
♪हमने एक दूसरे से जो वादा किया था♪
♪Every breeze carries your touch♪
♪हर हवा में तुम्हारा स्पर्श है♪
♪Kissing the warmth of my hand♪
♪मेरे हाथ की गर्माहट को चूमते हुए♪
♪So no matter how far it may be, don't hesitate♪
♪इसलिए चाहे दूरी कितनी भी हो, संकोच मत करो♪
♪Love will guide us through♪
♪प्रेम हमारा मार्गदर्शन करेगा♪
♪If the star path leads to the light-year's end♪
♪यदि तारा पथ प्रकाश वर्ष के अंत तक जाता है♪
♪Would I have met you a little sooner?♪
♪क्या मैं आपसे थोड़ा पहले मिल पाता?♪
♪Like night embracing the fireworks' glow♪
♪जैसे रात आतिशबाज़ी की चमक को गले लगा रही हो♪
♪You and I were meant to hold hands♪
♪तुम और मैं हाथ पकड़ने के लिए बने थे♪
♪If the star path leads to the light-year's end♪
♪यदि तारा पथ प्रकाश वर्ष के अंत तक जाता है♪
♪Would destiny have brought us together?♪
♪क्या भाग्य हमें साथ लाता?♪
♪Turning thorns into silver threads on a crown♪
♪काँटों को मुकुट पर चाँदी के धागों में बदलना♪
♪I'll weave them for you, forever around♪
♪मैं इन्हें तुम्हारे लिए बुनूंगी, हमेशा तुम्हारे आसपास♪
=Long Planned Love=
=लंबे समय से नियोजित प्रेम=
=Episode 24=
=एपिसोड 24=
(Zhou Yufeng)
(झोउ युफेंग)
Sorry,
क्षमा मांगना,
the number you dialed is currently unavailable.
आपके द्वारा डायल किया गया नंबर वर्तमान में अनुपलब्ध है.
Sorry,
क्षमा मांगना,
the number you dialed is currently unreachable.
आपके द्वारा डायल किया गया नंबर वर्तमान में पहुंच योग्य नहीं है।
Please try again later.
कृपया बाद में पुन: प्रयास करें।
Before this,
इस से पहले,
I never dared to hope for anything.
मैंने कभी किसी चीज़ की आशा करने की हिम्मत नहीं की।
I love you.
मुझे तुमसे प्यार है।
But today,
लेकिन आज,
I caught a glimpse of light.
मुझे प्रकाश की एक झलक दिखी।
I want to hold onto it.
मैं इसे थामे रखना चाहता हूं।
We'll face
हम सामना करेंगे
everything together.
सब कुछ एक साथ.
Yeah.
हाँ।
(I thought I had caught the light.)
(मुझे लगा कि मैंने प्रकाश पकड़ लिया है।)
(But light can't be held.)
(लेकिन प्रकाश को रोका नहीं जा सकता.)
Uncle Zhou has found out the truth.
चाचा झोउ को सच्चाई पता चल गई है।
Back then,
तो वापस,
it was Jian Wenqian
यह जियान वेनकियान था
who told her cousin
जिसने अपने चचेरे भाई को बताया
to abduct Jian Cheng.
जियान चेंग का अपहरण करने के लिए।
What did you just say?
आपने अभी अभी क्या कहा?
She's in the mountains.
वह पहाड़ों में है.
Can she not lose her dignity?
क्या वह अपनी गरिमा नहीं खो सकती?
Do you want people talking about you forever?
क्या आप चाहते हैं कि लोग हमेशा आपके बारे में बात करते रहें?
Son,
बेटा,
think about it.
इसके बारे में सोचो.
Your grandpa cared about your dad.
आपके दादाजी आपके पिता की परवाह करते थे।
If it hadn't been for your uncle,
अगर तुम्हारे चाचा न होते,
Qianyi Group
कियानयी समूह
would've belonged to your dad.
तुम्हारे पिता का होता।
And your dad's
और आपके पिताजी का
would've been yours.
तुम्हारा होता.
Jian Cheng saved
जियान चेंग को बचाया गया
your uncle at this point.
इस समय आपके चाचा.
She just doesn't love you.
वह तुमसे प्यार ही नहीं करती.
Trust me on this.
इस पर मेरा विश्वास करो.
I've protected myself.
मैंने अपनी रक्षा कर ली है।
Jian Cheng,
जियान चेंग,
I trust you.
मुझे आप पर विश्वास है।
But I'm just not ready yet.
लेकिन मैं अभी तैयार नहीं हूं.
(Turns out)
(पता चला है)
(when she needed me the most,)
(जब उसे मेरी सबसे ज्यादा जरूरत थी,)
(I trusted others and gave up on her.)
(मैंने दूसरों पर भरोसा किया और उस पर भरोसा करना छोड़ दिया।)
Yawei...
यावेई...
Does she know about this?
क्या वह इस बारे में जानती है?
Of course.
बिल्कुल।
A few people ganged up on you.
कुछ लोगों ने आप पर हमला कर दिया।
So you let go of Jian Cheng...
तो आपने जियान चेंग को जाने दिया...
Stop talking.
बात करना बंद करें।
You lost Qianyi...
आपने कियानयी को खो दिया...
Stop talking!
बात करना बंद करें!
It was bound to happen.
यह तो होना ही था।
Jiang Yawei.
जियांग यावेई.
Your own personal hell
आपका अपना निजी नरक
has arrived.
आ गया है.
If you want a better future,
यदि आप एक बेहतर भविष्य चाहते हैं,
listen to Mom's advice:
माँ की सलाह सुनो:
Get a divorce.
तलाक ले लो.
Before things turn ugly,
इससे पहले कि हालात बदतर हो जाएं,
ask for more money
अधिक पैसे मांगें
and move to another city.
और दूसरे शहर चले जाओ.
Live your own life well.
अपना जीवन अच्छे से जियो.
If you keep being stubborn,
यदि आप जिद्दी बने रहेंगे,
in the end,
अंततः,
this mismatched marriage
यह बेमेल विवाह
will drain you into someone bitter.
आपको किसी कड़वे व्यक्ति में बदल देगा।
Eventually,
अंततः,
you'll end up with nothing.
अंत में आपके हाथ कुछ भी नहीं आएगा।
Zhou Yufeng.
झोउ युफेंग.
Zhou Yufeng!
झोउ युफ़ेंग!
Speak.
बोलना।
Let's get divorced.
चलो तलाक ले लें.
Jiang Yawei,
जियांग यावेई,
in this lifetime,
इस जीवनकाल में,
I will never divorce you.
मैं तुम्हें कभी तलाक नहीं दूंगी.
Let go.
जाने दो.
Let me go.
मुझे जाने दो.
I wanted to apologize to Jian Cheng,
मैं जियान चेंग से माफ़ी मांगना चाहता था,
but now I can't even face her.
लेकिन अब मैं उसका सामना भी नहीं कर सकता.
If it weren't for all that happened,
यदि यह सब न हुआ होता,
maybe we could've been friends.
शायद हम दोस्त बन सकते थे.
So...
इसलिए...
you came to me,
तुम मेरे पास आये,
hoping I'd play peacemaker.
मुझे उम्मीद है कि मैं शांतिदूत की भूमिका निभाऊंगा।
Sorry.
क्षमा मांगना।
On this matter,
इस मामले में,
I'm siding with Cheng.
मैं चेंग का पक्ष ले रहा हूं।
I heard
मैंने सुन लिया।
you're concerned about Qin Zhuo and Mi Shan.
आप किन झूओ और मी शान के बारे में चिंतित हैं।
What are you trying to say?
आप क्या कहने की कोशिश कर रहे हैं?
Five years ago,
पांच साल पहले,
Mi Shan was drugged by her agent
मी शान को उसके एजेंट ने नशीला पदार्थ दिया था
and sent into Qin Zhuo's room.
और किन झुओ के कमरे में भेज दिया गया।
Qin Zhuo was too drunk,
किन झूओ बहुत नशे में था,
but he realized it and left.
लेकिन उसे इसका एहसास हो गया और वह चला गया।
A Sasaeng fan still
अभी भी सासेंग का प्रशंसक
snuck in and took photos.
चुपके से अंदर घुस गए और तस्वीरें ले लीं।
Next day, Mi Shan's scandalous photos were everywhere.
अगले दिन, मी शान की निंदनीय तस्वीरें हर जगह थीं।
Out of guilt,
अपराध बोध से,
Qin Zhuo claimed to be her boyfriend
किन झूओ ने उसका प्रेमी होने का दावा किया
and explained about the photos.
और फोटो के बारे में बताया।
It also saved her career.
इससे उसका करियर भी बच गया।
So,
इसलिए,
the two of them
वो दो
really had nothing going on.
वास्तव में कुछ भी नहीं चल रहा था.
Mm-hmm.
हाँ-हाँ.
Then...
तब...
why are you telling me all this?
तुम मुझे ये सब क्यों बता रहे हो?
Because
क्योंकि
you're someone important to Jian Cheng.
आप जियान चेंग के लिए महत्वपूर्ण व्यक्ति हैं।
If you're happy,
यदि आप खुश हैं,
Jian Cheng will be happy too.
जियान चेंग भी खुश होगा.
It's kind of
यह इस प्रकार का है
my way of making amends.
मेरे सुधार करने का तरीका.
I'm sorry.
मुझे माफ़ करें।
I want to speak for him
मैं उसके लिए बोलना चाहता हूँ
and apologize to you.
और आपसे क्षमा मांगता हूं.
Even his apology
यहां तक ​​कि उनकी माफी भी
has to come through you.
आपके माध्यम से आना होगा.
There are some things
कुछ चीजें हैं
I've wanted to tell you for a long time.
मैं तुम्हें बहुत समय से बताना चाहता था।
Don't say it.
ऐसा मत कहो.
I feel like
मन करता है
maybe being friends
शायद दोस्त होने के नाते
is better for us.
हमारे लिए बेहतर है.
♪When I met you, even the clouds forgot to breathe♪
♪जब मैं तुमसे मिला, तो बादल भी साँस लेना भूल गए♪
Tang,
तांग,
this formal handshake
यह औपचारिक हाथ मिलाना
feels a bit too much.
थोड़ा ज्यादा लगता है.
♪You said you wanted to forget our memories♪
♪तुमने कहा था कि तुम हमारी यादें भूलना चाहते हो♪
One last time.
एक आखिरी बार।
♪My heart is racing♪
♪मेरा दिल तेजी से धड़क रहा है♪
Let's just
बस चलो
give that frozen springtime cicada
उस जमे हुए वसंतकालीन सिकाडा को दे दो
a proper send-off.
एक उचित विदाई.
♪Through three lifetimes I turn, to meet you again♪
♪तीन जन्मों से मैं फिर से तुमसे मिलने के लिए मुड़ता हूँ♪
♪By unseen threads our souls are drawn♪
♪अदृश्य धागों से हमारी आत्माएँ खिंची जाती हैं♪
♪I run to you, a destined romance♪
♪मैं तुम्हारे पास दौड़ता हूँ, एक नियत रोमांस♪
♪Thanks to fate's gentle favor♪
♪भाग्य की कोमल कृपा के लिए धन्यवाद♪
♪You slipped right into my heart♪
♪तुम सीधे मेरे दिल में उतर गए♪
♪And filled the years of longing inside♪
♪और वर्षों की लालसा को अंदर भर दिया♪
Oh, right.
अरे हां।
Tell him,
उससे कहो,
what he broke
उसने क्या तोड़ा
was my moon.
मेरा चाँद था.
Have him apologize
उससे माफ़ी मांगो
to the night sky.
रात के आकाश में.
♪You're still my love in my heart♪
♪तुम अब भी मेरे दिल में मेरा प्यार हो♪
♪Time has taken away all we had♪
♪समय ने हमसे सब कुछ छीन लिया है♪
♪Yet memories quietly remain♪
♪फिर भी यादें चुपचाप बनी रहती हैं♪
You two held hands.
तुम दोनों ने हाथ पकड़ लिया।
Yeah.
हाँ।
We did hold hands.
हमने एक दूसरे का हाथ पकड़ा।
And we hugged.
और हम गले मिले.
We even...
हम तो यहां तक...
♪Falling softly all around us♪
♪हमारे चारों ओर धीरे-धीरे गिर रहा है♪
♪Those so-called worries♪
♪वे तथाकथित चिंताएँ♪
♪Turned into excuses to run away♪
♪भागने के बहाने बन गए♪
♪I'm too afraid to look back♪
♪मैं पीछे मुड़कर देखने से बहुत डरता हूँ♪
♪Your gentle touch♪
♪आपका कोमल स्पर्श♪
♪Lingers as my quiet companion♪
♪मेरे शांत साथी के रूप में रहता है♪
♪It became the reason I run to you without doubt♪
♪यही कारण है कि मैं बिना किसी संदेह के आपके पास दौड़ी आती हूँ♪
♪The moonlight turned our hair silver♪
♪चाँदनी ने हमारे बालों को चाँदी का रंग दे दिया♪
♪We said from now on♪
♪हमने कहा अब से♪
♪We'll walk together into the future♪
♪हम भविष्य में साथ-साथ चलेंगे♪
Can we remain engaged?
क्या हम जुड़े रह सकते हैं?
♪Drifting through the bustling crowd♪
♪भीड़-भाड़ के बीच से बहते हुए♪
♪I take your hand♪
♪मैं तुम्हारा हाथ थामता हूँ♪
♪Your gaze is gentler than the breeze♪
♪तुम्हारी निगाहें हवा से भी कोमल हैं♪
♪Time has taken away all we had♪
♪समय ने हमसे सब कुछ छीन लिया है♪
♪Yet memories quietly remain♪
♪फिर भी यादें चुपचाप बनी रहती हैं♪
♪My heart stirs when I meet you again♪
♪जब मैं तुमसे दोबारा मिलता हूँ तो मेरा दिल धड़कता है♪
♪In that fleeting exchange of glances♪
♪उस क्षणिक नज़रों के आदान-प्रदान में♪
♪The stars are lit up in the night♪
♪रात में तारे जगमगाते हैं♪
♪Falling softly all around us♪
♪हमारे चारों ओर धीरे-धीरे गिर रहा है♪
(Honey)
(शहद)
Today marks our 1st wedding anniversary.
आज हमारी शादी की पहली सालगिरह है।
It's also Valentine's Day.
आज वैलेंटाइन डे भी है।
Can we stop living apart?
क्या हम अलग रहना बंद कर सकते हैं?
Then be good.
तो फिर अच्छा बनो.
(Honey: Then be good.)
(हनी: तो फिर अच्छे बनो।)
Get changed.
कपड़े बदल लो.
♪If the star path leads to the light-year's end♪
♪यदि तारा पथ प्रकाश वर्ष के अंत तक जाता है♪
♪Would I have met you a little sooner?♪
♪क्या मैं आपसे थोड़ा पहले मिल पाता?♪
♪Like night embracing the fireworks' glow♪
♪जैसे रात आतिशबाज़ी की चमक को गले लगा रही हो♪
♪You and I were meant to hold hands♪
♪तुम और मैं हाथ पकड़ने के लिए बने थे♪
♪The tide has brought in the paper boat you folded♪
♪ज्वार तुम्हारी बनाई हुई कागज़ की नाव ले आया है♪
♪Like fate answering all my prayers♪
♪जैसे भाग्य मेरी सभी प्रार्थनाओं का उत्तर दे रहा हो♪
♪You lower your head to crown me♪
♪तुम अपना सिर नीचे करके मुझे ताज पहनाते हो♪
(Viewers, thank you for your love and support.)
(दर्शकों, आपके प्यार और समर्थन के लिए धन्यवाद ।)
(The End)
(अंत)
(Hope you get your wish.)
(आशा है आपकी इच्छा पूरी होगी।)
(Stay healthy; Be happy)
(स्वस्थ रहें; खुश रहें)
♪Maybe this story is just too classic♪
♪शायद यह कहानी बहुत ज़्यादा क्लासिक है♪
♪In the abyss, a garden was sown and remembered♪
♪अथाह गहराई में एक बगीचा बोया गया और याद किया गया♪
♪In the ruins, you raise the moon, though broken♪
♪खंडहरों में, तुम चाँद को उठाते हो, भले ही वह टूटा हुआ हो♪
♪I see the prophecy at dawn♪
♪मैं भोर में भविष्यवाणी देखता हूँ♪
♪If the star path leads to the light-year's end♪
♪यदि तारा पथ प्रकाश वर्ष के अंत तक जाता है♪
♪Would I have met you a little sooner?♪
♪क्या मैं आपसे थोड़ा पहले मिल पाता?♪
♪Like night embracing the fireworks' glow♪
♪जैसे रात आतिशबाज़ी की चमक को गले लगा रही हो♪
♪You and I were meant to hold hands♪
♪तुम और मैं हाथ पकड़ने के लिए बने थे♪
♪If the star path leads to the light-year's end♪
♪यदि तारा पथ प्रकाश वर्ष के अंत तक जाता है♪
♪Would destiny have brought us together?♪
♪क्या भाग्य हमें साथ लाता?♪
♪Turning thorns into silver threads on a crown♪
♪काँटों को मुकुट पर चाँदी के धागों में बदलना♪
♪I'll weave them for you, forever around♪
♪मैं इन्हें तुम्हारे लिए बुनूंगी, हमेशा तुम्हारे आसपास♪
♪In your eyes, I see twinkling starlight♪
♪तुम्हारी आँखों में, मुझे टिमटिमाती तारों की रोशनी दिखाई देती है♪
♪That's why I dare to face the whole world♪
♪इसीलिए मैं पूरी दुनिया का सामना करने की हिम्मत रखता हूँ♪
♪Even the universe♪
♪यहाँ तक कि ब्रह्मांड भी♪
♪Tacitly approves of the romantic vow♪
♪रोमांटिक प्रतिज्ञा को मौन स्वीकृति♪
♪Our love is the optimal solution♪
♪हमारा प्यार ही सर्वोत्तम समाधान है♪
♪The stars remember♪
♪सितारे याद रखते हैं♪
♪The promise we made to each other♪
♪हमने एक दूसरे से जो वादा किया था♪